JERUD Moyer

Software Developer

<u>jerud-moyer.dev</u>



(503) 201-0100



jerudmoyer@gmail.com



<u>jerud-moyer</u>



<u>Jerud-Moyer</u>

ABOUT ME

Full-Stack software developer with a background in fine-arts and customer service. Blending creativity with code to solve problems and always striving to make the results beautiful. I value shared experiences with teammates and clients alike.

TECH SKILLS

languages

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML
- CSS

testing

- Jest
- QUnit
- SuperTest

frameworks

& libraries

- Node.js
- Express
- PostgreSQL
- React
- Redux
- React -Native
- BCrypt

EDUCATION

Alchemy Code Lab 2020

6 months of intense code immersion with focus on JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express and PostgreSQL. Here I learned many tools for advanced problem solving.

Portland Community College 1994 - 1997

Fine Arts, focused on life painting and drawing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Alchemy Code Lab 1/2021-6/2021

Software Development Teaching Assistant
Teaching the next generation of developers. Focused on
JavaScript, React, Node.js and PostgreSQL.

Goldrush Coffee Bar 2004-2020

Owner / Operator

Community and quality were paramount to the vision. Here I learned many sides of small business operations including actively supporting the local community, hiring and management of staff, inventory management, bookkeeping, accounting and customer relations. Problem solving was the common thread woven throughout my many daily tasks. My intuition and experience served me well in creating this beloved gathering place.

FREELANCE WORK

Amphead-Lanham 2021

visit the site

Designed and developed this full-stack web app for a multi-faceted Portland business. Amphead services musical equipment and Lanham builds custom guitar amplifiers. One website that acts as two. A NodeJS/Express backend API with PostgreSQL database, serves the data. A React/Redux front end brings it all to the consumer. Protected routes with full authorization allow the site owner to manage content through an administrator UI.

michaelalbano.art 2021

visit the site

Created this artist's gallery with React and TypeScript on the front end and NodeJS, utilizing the Cloudinary API on the back. The artist can upload their own high quality images and manage all their own content with a protected admin route.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Mood Music

React, Redux, Node, PostgreSQL, Heroku, MS Azure, Spotify API <u>site</u> <u>github</u>

An app that captures a user's mood and returns a perfect playlist.

Project Vobot

Node, PostgreSQL, Jest, Heroku, Twilio, Twitter API

site github

In a four day remote sprint, my team and I built a pair of bots to deliver state-specific voter information to users.

nerdMeme

Node, PostgreSQL, React-Native

<u>github</u>

A random meme generator for Android..